# **ALEX POMA**

## Data Engineer Specialist

**>** +51 973119856

alex.poma.iis@gmail.com

alexpoma.github.io





I'm passionate about data, I'm currently working at Rimac Seguros as Data Engineer Specialist. I consider myself a self-taught person, who loves technology and process automation, I have been fortunate to cooperate with wonderful teamworks, participating in the different phases of the development of pipelines. I have been working with data for several years, also have the ease to work in a team, as well as efficiently solve problems and achieve the productivity goals set by the company and my teamwork.

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

#### **Data Engineer Specialist**

Rimac Seguros | Feb 2022 - Now

I'm part of the Tribu Data, a member of the Support GCP team, responsible for the creation of different Data Pipelines and their deployment using different GCP technologies.

- Development of Airflow's DAGs for data ingest and improvement of monitoring processes.
- Cloud Functions creation for automation process.
- Implementation of the proceso automático, for the automatic execution of DAGs.
- Review of DataFlow processes for Data Entries loading.
- Process scheduling with Cloud Scheduler.
- Creating of tables and scripts in BigQuery.
- Deployment pipelines in Jenkins for deploy in GCP.
- Use of Agile methodologies complemented with Scrum.

GCP | Cloud Function | Composer | Airflow | Cloud Scheduler | BiqQuery | DataFlow | Looker Studio | Python | Git | Jenkins

#### **Data Engineer**

TCS | Nov 2020 - Feb 2022

Was member of the AWS Support team, responsible for creating and maintaining different data pipelines using Cloud technologies and SCRUM methodologies.

- Part of the RIMAC Seguros project for the implementation of the BigData ecosystems on AWS.
- Create workflows using AWS Step Function.
- Creation of Python Jobs on AWS Glue for data processing automation.
- Triggers generation in AWS Lambda.
- Scheduling works with AWS CloudWatch.
- Creation of tables and scripts in Athena and Redshift.
- Implementation and optimization of scripts in Presto SQL.
- Logs review, correction and optimization of potential errors.
- Creation and optimization of Dashboards using Power Bl.

AWS | Lambda | Glue | Step Function | CloudWatch | Athena | Redshift | Python | Presto SQL | PowerBI | Power Automate

#### Analista de Inteligencia de Negocios

CMAC Tacna | Jun 2018 - Nov 2020

Inside the Caja Tacna I had the opportunity to learn many things about the financial system, also to being part of the Business Intelligence and Analytical Solutions area, where I was able to generate and optimize Scripts in SQLServer, use ETL tools to create OLAP cubes and the generation of Power BI Dashboards.

- $\bullet$  Implementation and administration of the Data Warehouse.
- Generation of credit reports using SSRS.
- Generation of data load packages using SSIS.
- $\bullet$  Implementation of OLAP Cubes using SSAS, for the generation of managerial reports.
- Automating the SBS Data Extraction Process using SSIS and R.
- Times reduction for the generation of financial periods, with the implementation of an OLAP Cube.
- Implementation of Dashboards using Power Bl.
- Generation and improvement of Scripts in SQL Server.
- Implementation of the Sinergia project that covers the most used and most important reports and management boards for the company's decision making.

SSIS | SSRS | SSAS | PowerBI | MSQL Server | R | DAX | MDX

## SKILLS

#### **Technicals**

Python/SQL/R

AWS/GCP

Spark/Airflow

Big Data

Data Pipelines

Machine Learning

Data Visualization

#### **Professionals**

Effective communication

Teamwork

Problem solver

Good time management

## EDUCATION

## Eng. in Computer Science and Systems

Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University

2011 - 2015

## LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)
English (Professional)
Portugués (Professional)

## INTERESTS

Swimming

Photography

Programming

Cartoons